Diane Wolkstein collection
American Folklife Center, Library of Congress
- Series 5: Marketing and Publicity
  - Subseries 3: Audio and Video
    - Weekend Edition/Sunday "Diane Wolkstein", June 14, 1992
      - Sound cassette version, AFC 2016/057: SR286; 1 sound cassette
    - WNBC-TV Today in New York - Weekend interview with Diane Wolkstein, June 5, 1999
      - U-matic version, AFC 2016/057: MV327; 1 videocassette (U-matic)
      - U-matic version, AFC 2016/057: MV328; 1 videocassette (U-matic)
    - WNYE "Journey to the West", undated, AFC 2016/057: MV332; 1 videocassette (DVCam)
    - WP Radio, December 26, 2003, AFC 2016/057: SR287; 1 sound cassette
- Series 6: Administrative Files
  Publishing contracts and business correspondence related to Wolkstein's career as a professional storyteller.
  - 8,000 Stones contracts, 1987-1999 (Box-folder 16/1)
  - Awakening to the Day publisher correspondence, 1994-1995, 1 folder of manuscript materials (Box-folder 16/2)
  - Banza contracts, 1980-1986, 1 folder of manuscript materials (Box-folder 19/5)
  - Bouki Dances the Kokioko contracts, 1997-2003, 1 folder of manuscript materials (Box-folder 16/3)
  - Celebrate Story Festival, 2007, 1 folder of manuscript materials (Box-folder 16/4)
  - Celebrate Story Festival, 2008, 1 folder of manuscript materials (Box-folder 16/5)
  - Celebrate Story Festival poster, 2008, afc2016057_dc270; 2 color photographs (JPG, PSD)
  - Celebrating Our Mistakes contract, 2004, 1 folder of manuscript materials (Box-folder 16/6)
  - China's First Elephant contracts, 1969, 1 folder of manuscript materials (Box-folder 16/7)
  - Cloudstone correspondence, 1973-1989, 1 folder of manuscript materials (Box-folder 16/8)
  - The Contest contracts, 1993-1994, 1 folder of manuscript materials (Box-folder 19/6)
  - The Cool Ride in the Sky contracts, 1972-1974, 1 folder of manuscript materials (Box-folder 19/7)
  - Correspondence, 1968-1979, 1 folder of manuscript materials (Box-folder 16/9)
  - Correspondence, 1980-1989, 1 folder of manuscript materials (Box-folder 16/10)
  - Correspondence, 1990-1999, 1 folder of manuscript materials (Box-folder 16/11)
  - Correspondence, 2000-2012, undated, 1 folder of manuscript materials (Box-folder 16/12)
  - Correspondence with publishers, 1975-1976, 1 folder of manuscript materials (Box-folder 16/13)
  - Correspondence with publishers, 1993-1995, 1 folder of manuscript materials (Box-folder 16/14)
  - Esther's Story contracts, 1992-2002, 1 folder of manuscript materials (Box-folder 19/8)
  - Festival, June 22-23, 2007, 1 folder of manuscript materials (Box-folder 16/15)
  - First Love Stories contracts, 1982-1990, 1 folder of manuscript materials (Box-folder 19/9)
  - The Glass Mountain contracts, 1995, 1 folder of manuscript materials (Box-folder 19/10)
  - Grant applications, 1976-1989, 1 folder of manuscript materials (Box-folder 19/11)
  - Grant applications, 1994-2004, 1 folder of manuscript materials (Box-folder 16/16)
  - The Grass Slipper contract, 1994, 1 folder of manuscript materials (Box-folder 16/17)
  - Inanna contracts, 1983-2011, 1 folder of manuscript materials (Box-folder 19/12)
  - Jewish holiday stories contracts, 1997, 1 folder of manuscript materials (Box-folder 19/13)
  - Lazy Stories contracts, 1976-1981, 1 folder of manuscript materials (Box-folder 19/14)
  - The Legend of Sleepy Hollow contracts, 1994, 1 folder of manuscript materials (Box-folder 16/18)
  - The Little Banjo contracts, 2000, 1 folder of manuscript materials (Box-folder 19/15)
  - Little Mouse's Painting contracts, 2001, 1 folder of manuscript materials (Box-folder 16/19)
  - The Magic Orange Trees contracts, 1978-2007, 1 folder of manuscript materials (Box-folder 19/16)
  - The Magic Orange Trees publisher correspondence, 1994-1995, 1 folder of manuscript materials (Box-folder 17/1)
  - The Magic Wings contracts, 1985-1990, 1 folder of manuscript materials (Box-folder 17/2)
  - The Monkey King grants, 2007-2009, 1 folder of manuscript materials (Box-folder 17/3)
  - National Storytelling Festival, 1977, 1 folder of manuscript materials (Box-folder 17/4)
  - Norwegian Storytelling Festival, 2012, 1 folder of manuscript materials (Box-folder 17/5)
  - Ocean Visits Sun and Moon contracts, 1997-2009, 1 folder of manuscript materials (Box-folder 17/6)
  - Oom Razoom contracts, 1989-1999, 1 folder of manuscript materials (Box-folder 20/1)
  - Owl contracts, 1990, 1 folder of manuscript materials (Box-folder 17/7)
  - Recording contracts, 1985-1997, 1 folder of manuscript materials (Box-folder 17/8)
  - The Red Lion contracts, 1976, 1 folder of manuscript materials (Box-folder 20/2)
  - Romping contracts, 2002, 1 folder of manuscript materials (Box-folder 17/9)
  - Squirrel's Song contracts, 1976-1986, 1 folder of manuscript materials (Box-folder 20/3)
  - Step by Step contracts, 1990, 1 folder of manuscript materials (Box-folder 20/4)
  - Story licensing agreements, 1992, 1 folder of manuscript materials (Box-folder 20/5)
  - Storyteller-in-residence contracts, 2007, 1 folder of manuscript materials (Box-folder 17/10)
  - Sun Mother Wakes the World contracts, 1994, 1 folder of manuscript materials (Box-folder 20/6)
  - The Visit contracts, 1977-1983, 1 folder of manuscript materials (Box-folder 20/7)
  - The White Wave contracts, 1978-2004, 1 folder of manuscript materials (Box-folder 20/8)
- Series 7: Workshops and Teaching
  Manuscripts and audio and video recordings related to Wolkstein's work teaching storytelling.
  - Subseries 1: Manuscripts and Photographic Prints
    - How to Tell Stories teaching notes, undated, 1 folder of manuscript materials (Box-folder 17/11)
    - Kaohsiung storytelling workshop, undated, 1 folder of manuscript materials (Box-folder 17/12)
    - Storytelling, Bank Street College, 1990, 1 folder of manuscript materials (Box-folder 17/13)
    - Storytelling class, 1993, 1 folder of manuscript materials (Box-folder 17/14)
    - Storytelling seminar, 1987, 1 folder of manuscript materials (Box-folder 17/15)
    - Storytelling to Children Five and Under course reading list, circa 1970, 1 folder of manuscript materials (Box-folder 17/16)
    - Storytelling workshops, 1988-1989, 1 folder of manuscript materials (Box-folder 17/17)
    - Storytelling workshop, April 23, 1995, 1 folder of manuscript materials (Box-folder 17/18)
    - Storytelling workshops, undated, 1 folder of manuscript materials (Box-folder 17/19)
    - Teaching contracts, 1978-1990, 1 folder of manuscript materials (Box-folder 17/20)
    - Teaching Storytelling, 1988, 1 folder of manuscript materials (Box-folder 17/21)
    - Teaching and workshops, 1994-2003, 1 folder of manuscript materials (Box-folder 17/22)
    - Workshop for parents, circa 1990, 1 folder of manuscript materials (Box-folder 17/23)
  - Subseries 2: Audio and Video
    - Bank Street College Teaching Storytelling, April 18, 1990, AFC 2016/057: MV282; 1 videocassette (VHS)
    - Egypt Lecture, April 1988, AFC 2016/057: SR288; 1 sound cassette
    - May Time Storytelling Celebration discussion, May 2, 1999, AFC 2016/057: SR289; 1 sound cassette
    - Politics and History of Storytelling #3, undated, AFC 2016/057: SR290; 1 sound cassette
    - Religion and Storytelling #4, undated, AFC 2016/057: SR291; 1 sound cassette
    - Seeing the Word, Hearing the Word, Diane Wolkstein's Keynote - Sharing the Fire, 1999, AFC 2016/057: SR292; 1 sound cassette
    - Storyteller as Researcher, March 11, 1998
      - Part 1, AFC 2016/057: SR293; 1 sound cassette
      - Part 2, AFC 2016/057: SR294; 1 sound cassette
    - Storyteller Workshop: Diane Wolkstein and Paul Jordan Smith, April 8, 1981, AFC 2016/057: SR295; 1 sound cassette
    - Storytelling Workshop, November 5, 2006
      - Part 1, AFC 2016/057: MV118; 1 videocassette (MiniDV)
      - Part 2, AFC 2016/057: MV119; 1 videocassette (MiniDV)
    - Storytelling Center, Conversation with Diane Wolkstein, December 10, 1991, AFC 2016/057: SR296; 1 sound cassette
    - Storytelling Class, undated, AFC 2016/057: SR297; 1 sound cassette
    - Storytelling Skills Workshop, March 24, 2012, afc2016057_dc479; 1 video file (MPG)
    - Storytelling Workshop 3, undated, AFC 2016/057: SR298; 1 sound cassette
    - Women's Workshop, April 20, 1985, AFC 2016/057: SR299; 1 sound cassette
    - Workshop - Storytelling, undated, AFC 2016/057: SR300; 1 sound cassette
- Series 8: A Storyteller's Story documentary production files
  Production files and uncut audio recordings and video footage used to create Wolkstein's self-published documentary, A Storyteller's Story.
  - Subseries 1: Manuscripts and Photographic Prints
    - Archival photographs used in A Storyteller's Story, undated, afc2016057_dc256; 216 color and black-and-white photographs (JPG)
    - A Storyteller's Story production files, 2007, 1 folder of manuscript materials (Box-folder 17/24)
    - Haiti photographs used in A Storyteller's Story, undated, afc2016057_dc294; Retouched March 29, 2007; 34 black-and-white photographs (JPG)
  - Subseries 2: Audio and Video
    Arranged alphabetically by carrier title. Duplicate content may exist throughout. The archivist has paired duplicate content together when possible.
    - AAIM Annual Meeting, Diane Wolkstein, January 30, 2007, AFC 2016/057: MV120; 1 videocassette (MiniDV)
    - Anita interview, February 2007, afc2016057_dc315; 8 video files (IFO, VOB, BUP)
    - Anita interview, March 27, 2007, AFC 2016/057: MV121; 1 videocassette (MiniDV)
    - Camera 1, March 16, 2007
      - MiniDV version, AFC 2016/057: MV122; 1 videocassette (MiniDV)
      - MiniDV version, AFC 2016/057: MV123; 1 videocassette (MiniDV)
    - Camera 1 dub, June 8, 2007, AFC 2016/057: MV125; 1 videocassette (MiniDV)
    - Camera 1 dub, June 13, 2007, AFC 2016/057: MV124; 1 videocassette (MiniDV)
    - Camera 2, March 16, 2007
      - MiniDV version, AFC 2016/057: MV126; 1 videocassette (MiniDV)
      - MiniDV version, AFC 2016/057: MV127; 1 videocassette (MiniDV)
    - Camera 2 dub, June 13, 2007
      - MiniDV version, AFC 2016/057: MV128; 1 videocassette (MiniDV)
      - MiniDV version, AFC 2016/057: MV129; 1 videocassette (MiniDV)
    - Chappaqua, undated, AFC 2016/057: MV130; 1 videocassette (MiniDV)
    - Diane does Tai Chi/Stories, June 2, 2007, AFC 2016/057: MV131; 1 videocassette (MiniDV)
    - Diane on Piddock Day, September 17, 2005, AFC 2016/057: MV132; 1 videocassette (MiniDV)
    - Diane Wolkstein at Hans Christian Andersen Statue with John Jacobs, September 16, 1995
      - Part 1, AFC 2016/057: MV133; 1 videocassette (MiniDV)
      - Part 2, AFC 2016/057: MV134; 1 videocassette (MiniDV)
    - Diane Wolkstein Central Park, June 5, 2004, AFC 2016/057: MV135; 1 videocassette (MiniDV)
    - Diane Wolkstein interview, February 26, 2007, AFC 2016/057: MV136; 1 videocassette (MiniDV)
    - Diane Wolkstein interview, March 4, 2007
      - MiniDV version, AFC 2016/057: MV137; 1 videocassette (MiniDV)
      - DVD version, afc2016057_dc292; 11 video files (IFO, VOB, BUP)
    - Diane Wolkstein interview, undated, AFC 2016/057: MV138; 1 videocassette (MiniDV)
    - Diane Wolkstein interview pick up, July 19, 2007, AFC 2016/057: MV139; 1 videocassette (MiniDV)
    - Diane Wolkstein introduction storyteller, March 1, 2007, AFC 2016/057: MV140; 1 videocassette (MiniDV)
    - Diane Wolkstein with Moses and Abram, March 1, 2007, AFC 2016/057: MV143; 1 videocassette (MiniDV)
    - Diane Wolkstein workshop in Austin, Texas, 2/2, January 2007, AFC 2016/057: MV144; 1 videocassette (MiniDV)
    - Diane Wolkstein, Elsie Piddock Skips in Her Sleep at Hans Christian Andersen Statue, September 22, 1996
      - Part 1, AFC 2016/057: MV146; 1 videocassette (MiniDV)
      - Part 2, AFC 2016/057: MV147; 1 videocassette (MiniDV)
    - Diane Wolkstein, Elsie Piddock Skips in Her Sleep at Hans Christian Andersen II, September 20, 1997, AFC 2016/057: MV145; 1 videocassette (MiniDV)
    - Diane Wolkstein's 40th anniversary celebration, June 22, 2007
      - MiniDV version, AFC 2016/057: MV148; 1 videocassette (MiniDV)
      - DVD version, afc2016057_dc321; 7 video files (IFO, VOB, BUP)
    - Esther, 1996, AFC 2016/057: MV149; 1 videocassette (MiniDV)
    - Exodus at American Museum of Natural History, April 11, 1999, AFC 2016/057: MV150; 1 videocassette (MiniDV)
    - Exodus rehearsal, undated, AFC 2016/057: MV151; 1 videocassette (MiniDV)
    - Extras - The Dreaming, undated, afc2016057_dc286; 7 video files (IFO, VOB, BUP)
    - Extras - Hans Clodhopper, undated, afc2016057_dc055; Performed at the Dodge Poetry Festival; 7 video files (IFO, VOB, BUP)
    - Extras - Tipengee, undated, afc2016057_dc290; 7 video files (IFO, VOB, BUP)
    - Extras - The Water Spirit, undated, afc2016057_dc293; 11 video files (IFO, VOB, BUP)
    - Felix Augustin, March 30, 2007, AFC 2016/057: MV152; 1 videocassette (MiniDV)
    - Gioia interview, February 2007, afc2016057_dc300; 9 video files (IFO, VOB, BUP)
    - Gospel Monday night field recording, undated, afc2016057_dc281; 1 sound file (WAV)
    - Haitian Songs and Stories Hans Christian Andersen statue, September 20, 1997
      - Part 1, AFC 2016/057: MV157; 1 videocassette (MiniDV)
      - Part 2B, AFC 2016/057: MV156; 1 videocassette (MiniDV)
    - Haitian Songs and Stories Hans Christian Andersen statue, June 26, 1999
      - Part 1A, AFC 2016/057: MV153; 1 videocassette (MiniDV)
      - Part 1B, AFC 2016/057: MV154; 1 videocassette (MiniDV)
      - Part 2A, AFC 2016/057: MV155; 1 videocassette (MiniDV)
    - Harlem Day 1, excerpts, March 2007, afc2016057_dc303; 7 video files (IFO, VOB, BUP)
    - Harlem Day 3, April 20, 2007
      - Part 1 - MiniDV, AFC 2016/057: MV158; 1 videocassette (MiniDV)
      - Part 1 - MiniDV, AFC 2016/057: MV159; 1 videocassette (MiniDV)
      - Part 2 - MiniDV, AFC 2016/057: MV160; 1 videocassette (MiniDV)
    - Harlem school shoot, undated
      - Part 1, AFC 2016/057: MV161; 1 videocassette (MiniDV)
      - Part 2, AFC 2016/057: MV162; 1 videocassette (MiniDV)
      - Part 3, AFC 2016/057: MV163; 1 videocassette (MiniDV)
      - Part 4, AFC 2016/057: MV164; 1 videocassette (MiniDV)
    - Historic Diane Wolkstein - After Skip Rope Contest and Party, September 21, 1996
      - Part 1, AFC 2016/057: MV166; 1 videocassette (MiniDV)
      - Part 2, AFC 2016/057: MV165; 1 videocassette (MiniDV)
    - Hugh Vandusen interview, February 28, 2007
      - MiniDV version, AFC 2016/057: MV167; 1 videocassette (MiniDV)
      - DVD version, afc2016057_dc322; 7 video files (IFO, VOB, BUP)
    - Inanna Camera 1, undated
      - Reel 1, AFC 2016/057: MV168; 1 videocassette (MiniDV)
      - Reel 2, AFC 2016/057: MV169; 1 videocassette (MiniDV)
    - Inanna Camera 2, undated
      - Reel 1, AFC 2016/057: MV170; 1 videocassette (MiniDV)
      - Reel 2, AFC 2016/057: MV171; 1 videocassette (MiniDV)
    - Indian woman singing field recording, undated, afc2016057_dc283; 2 sound files (WAV)
    - Interview clips, undated, afc2016057_dc299; 7 video files (IFO, VOB, BUP)
    - Japanese Buddhist chanting, undated
      - Part 1, afc2016057_dc276; 1 sound file (WAV)
      - Part 2, afc2016057_dc277; 1 sound file (WAV)
    - Joya, undated, AFC 2016/057: MV172; 1 videocassette (MiniDV)
    - Macaya Rara - Folklore d'Haiti, undated, afc2016057_dc279; 10 sound files (WAV)
    - Magic Orange Tree and Others, June 3, 2007, AFC 2016/057: MV173; 1 videocassette (MiniDV)
    - Melissa interview, February 2007, afc2016057_dc304; 10 video files (IFO, VOB, BUP)
    - Melissa interview raw footage, April 3, 2007, AFC 2016/057: MV174; 1 videocassette (MiniDV)
    - Monkey King, undated
      - Part 1, AFC 2016/057: MV175; 1 videocassette (MiniDV)
      - Part 2, AFC 2016/057: MV176; 1 videocassette (MiniDV)
    - Moses and Abram interview, February 2007, afc2016057_dc295; 8 video files (IFO, VOB, BUP)
    - Music of the Kalahari, undated, afc2016057_dc280; Joh Brearly; 24 sound files (WAV)
    - North American flute music, undated, afc2016057_dc284; From the album Changes by R. Carlos Nakai, Canyon Records, 1982; 13 sound files (WAV)
    - Olivier interview, February 2007
      - MiniDV version, AFC 2016/057: MV177; 1 videocassette (MiniDV)
      - DVD version, afc2016057_dc291; 9 video files (IFO, VOB, BUP)
    - Phoebe Roosevelt interview, March 2007, afc2016057_dc318; 8 video files (IFO, VOB, BUP)
    - Popular songs from Greece, undated, afc2016057_dc278; 6 sound files (WAV)
    - Rachel Zucker interview, February 28, 2007, AFC 2016/057: MV178; 1 videocassette (MiniDV)
    - Rachel Zucker interview, March 2007, afc2016057_dc297; 9 video files (IFO, VOB, BUP)
    - Ray Joseph interview, April 19, 2007
      - MiniDV version, AFC 2016/057: MV179; 1 videocassette (MiniDV)
      - DVD version, afc2016057_dc319; 8 video files (IFO, VOB, BUP)
    - Regina Ross interview, March 2007
      - MiniDV version, AFC 2016/057: MV180; 1 videocassette (MiniDV)
      - DVD version, afc2016057_dc301; 9 video files (IFO, VOB, BUP)
    - Richard interview, March 3, 2007
      - MiniDV version, AFC 2016/057: MV181; 1 videocassette (MiniDV)
      - DVD version, afc2016057_dc302; 9 video files (IFO, VOB, BUP)
    - Sat interview, March 2007, afc2016057_dc316; 8 video files (IFO, VOB, BUP)
    - Shirley Keller interview, March 3, 2007
      - Part 1, AFC 2016/057: MV182; 1 videocassette (MiniDV)
      - Part 2, AFC 2016/057: MV183; 1 videocassette (MiniDV)
      - DVD version, afc2016057_dc285; 9 video files (IFO, VOB, BUP)
    - A Storyteller's Story, June 22, 2007, AFC 2016/057: MV184; 1 videocassette (MiniDV)
    - A Storyteller's Story, August 14, 2007, afc2016057_dc288; 9 video files (IFO, VOB, BUP)
    - Storytelling in school, undated, afc2016057_dc298; 6 video files (IFO, VOB, BUP)
    - Tai Chi lesson and interview with Sat, undated, AFC 2016/057: MV185; 1 videocassette (MiniDV)
    - Tai Qi Austin Workshop, January 2007, AFC 2016/057: MV186; 1 videocassette (MiniDV)
    - Treasures of the Heart, October 28, 2003
      - Part 1, AFC 2016/057: MV187; 1 videocassette (MiniDV)
      - Part 2, AFC 2016/057: MV188; 1 videocassette (MiniDV)
    - Treasures of the Heart offshots, undated, AFC 2016/057: MV189; 1 videocassette (MiniDV)
    - [Unlabeled], undated, AFC 2016/057: MV190; 1 videocassette (MiniDV)
    - [Unlabeled], undated, AFC 2016/057: MV191; 1 videocassette (MiniDV)
    - Wolkstein Storytelling, undated, AFC 2016/057: MV192; 1 videocassette (MiniDV)
    - Wolkstein Storytelling, undated, AFC 2016/057: MV193; 1 videocassette (MiniDV)
    - Wolkstein Storytelling, undated, AFC 2016/057: MV194; 1 videocassette (MiniDV)
    - Wolkstein Storytelling, undated, AFC 2016/057: MV195; 1 videocassette (MiniDV)
    - Zambia: Amachushi field recording, undated, afc2016057_dc282; 10 sound files (WAV)
    - Diane Wolkstein optical soundtrack, August 3, 2006
      - Part 1, AFC 2016/057: SR301; 1 sound cassette (DAT)
      - Part 2, AFC 2016/057: SR302; 1 sound cassette (DAT)
    - A Storyteller's Story audio mix, June 20, 2007, afc2016057_dc273; 1 sound file (AIFF)
- Optical media, CDs and DVDs containing the digital files described throughout the container list.; 244 audio discs (CD); 145 videodiscs (DVD) (Box 23-33)
Related Publications
Andersen, Hans Christian. Hans Christian Andersen Classic Stories. Narrated by Diane Wolkstein and accompanied by Shirley Keller. Little Rock, AR: August House Audio, 2005. CD.
Andersen, Hans Christian. Hans Christian Andersen in Central Park. Narrated by Diane Wolkstein. Weston, CT: Weston Woods, 1981. CD.
Courlander, Harold. Tales of the Hopi Indians. Narrated by Diane Wolkstein. 1975. Sound cassette.
Psyche and Eros. Translated and narrated by Diane Wolkstein. Montvale, NJ: Cloudstone Productions, 1984. Sound cassette.
Shannon, Monica. The Artistic Pig. Narrated by Diane Wolkstein. 1974. Sound cassette.
Shannon, Monica. The Bean Boy. Narrated by Diane Wolkstein. 1974. Sound cassette.
Shannon, Monica. Diane Wolkstein Tells California Fairy Tales. Narrated by Diane Wolkstein. 1985. Sound cassette.
Shannon, Monica. An Enchanted Gypsy. Narrated by Diane Wolkstein. 1974. Sound cassette.
Shannon, Monica. The First Hat. Narrated by Diane Wolkstein. 1974. Sound cassette.
Wolkstein, Diane. The Banza: A Haitian Story. Illustrated by Marc Brown. New York: Dial Books for Young Readers, 1981.
Wolkstein, Diane. Bouki Dances the Kokioko: A Comical Tale from Haiti. Illustrated by Jesse Sweetwater. San Diego, CA: Harcourt Brace, 2001.
Wolkstein, Diane. The Cool Ride in the Sky. Illustrated by Paul Galdone. New York: Alfred A. Knopf, 1973.
Wolkstein, Diane. The Day the Ocean Came to Visit. Illustrated by Steve Johnson and Lou Fancher. San Diego, CA: Harcourt, 2001.
Wolkstein, Diane. Dream Songs: Abulafia, Part of My Heart. New York: Cloudstone, 1991.
Wolkstein, Diane. The Epic of Inanna. Narrated by Diane Wolkstein. Music by Geoffrey Gordon. Montvale, NJ: Cloudstone, 1986. Sound cassette.
Wolkstein, Diane. Eskimo Stories. Narrated by Diane Wolkstein. Music by Avraham Qanai and L.S. Messina. New Rochelle, NY: Spoken Arts, 1985. Sound cassette.
Wolkstein, Diane. Esther's Story. Illustrated by Juan Wijingaard. New York: Morrow Junior Books, 1996.
Wolkstein, Diane. Estonian Fairy Tales. Narrated by Diane Wolkstein. Translated by Selve Maas. Music by Lilian Esop. D. Wolkstein, 1988. Sound cassette.
Wolkstein, Diane. The First Love Stories: From Isis and Osiris to Tristan and Iseult. New York: Harper Collins, 1991.
Wolkstein, Diane. The Glass Mountain. Illustrated by Louisa Bauer. New York: Morrow Junior Books, 1999.
Wolkstein, Diane. Lazy Stories. Illustrated by James Marshall. New York: The Seabury Press, 1976.
Wolkstein, Diane. The Legend of Sleepy Hollow: Based on the Story by Washington Irving. Illustrated by R.W. Alley. New York: William Morrow and Company, 1987.
Wolkstein, Diane. Little Mouse's Painting. Illustrated by Maryjane Begin. New York: Morrow Junior Books, 1992.
Wolkstein, Diane. The Magic Orange Tree, and Other Haitian Folktales. Illustrated by Elsa Henriquez. New York: Alfred A. Knopf, 1978.
Wolkstein, Diane. The Magic Wings: A Tale from China. Illustrated by Robert Andrew Parker. New York: Dutton, 1983.
Wolkstein, Diane. Oom Razoom, or Go I Know Not Where, Bring Back I Know Not What: A Russian Tale. Illustrated by Dennis McDermott. New York: Morrow Junior Books, 1991.
Wolkstein, Diane. Owl: A Folktale from Haiti in the Caribbean. Illustrated by Tracey Fennell. London, UK: BBC Educational Publishing, 1991.
Wolkstein, Diane. The Red Lion: A Tale of Ancient Persia. Illustrated by Ed Young. New York: Crowell, 1977.
Wolkstein, Diane. Romping. Narrated by Diane Wolkstein. Music by Shirley Keller. Montvale, NJ: Cloudstone Productions, 1985. Sound cassette.
Wolkstein, Diane. Squirrel's Song: A Hopi Indian Tale. Illustrated by Lillian Hoban. New York: Alfred A. Knopf, 1976.
Wolkstein, Diane. Step by Step. Illustrated by Joseph A. Smith. New York: Morrow Junior Books, 1994.
Wolkstein, Diane. The Story of Joseph: Its Scriptures and Midrash. Narrated by Diane Wolkstein. Montvale, NJ: Cloudstone, 1986.
Wolkstein, Diane. Sun Mother Wakes the World: An Australian Creation Story. Illustrated by Bronwyn Bancroft. New York: Harper Collins, 2004.
Wolkstein, Diane. Treasures of the Heart: Holiday Stories that Reveal the Soul of Judaism. New York: Schocken Books, 2003.
Wolkstein, Diane. The Visit. Illustrated by Lois Ehlert. New York: Alfred A. Knopf, 1977.
Wolkstein, Diane. White Wave: A Chinese Tale. Illustrated by Ed Young. New York: Thomas Y. Crowell Company, 1979.
Wolkstein, Diane and Samuel Noah Kramer. Inanna, Queen of Heaven and Earth: Her Stories and Hymns from Sumer. Art compiled by Elizabeth Williams-Forte. New York: Harper and Row, 1983.